# Ong Guo Xiang

# DESIGNER. ARCHITECT. RESEARCHER.

Email: ong.guoxiang@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ongguoxiang

Location: Github: https://github.com/gxite Singapore Portfolio: Skype ID: https://gxite.github.io live:ong.guoxiang 1

I am a Research Assistant with the National University of Singapore, Department of Architecture since July of 2019. Prior to this, I had spent 2 years working as an Architectural Associate in Singapore, taking on both project management and design roles.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Research Assistant**

National University of Singapore

Jul 2019 – Present

I process videos and images using Machine Learning models, performs spatial analysis on the data.

Project: Measuring Physical Profile and Use of Park Connector Network with Deep Learning and Multi-Source Multi-Modal Data Analytics

- Set up and maintained the software and hardware environment to perform object and action detections using Machine Learning models.
- Adapted python scripts from an open sourced research on real time action detections to work on large numbers of simultaneous detection on long pre-recorded video files.
- Wrote python scripts to process to the resulting detections for analysis within ArcGIS.
- Responsible for documenting all research related data and methodologies.

#### **Architectural Associate**

DCA Architects Pte Ltd

Jun 2017 – Jun 2019

I have designed facilities for condominiums, managed construction contracts and worked on computational design on the sides.

- Worked as a Design Architect in collaboration with local consultant teams in Vietnam for the design of a condominium complex and show gallery in Ho Chi Minh City. Designed auxiliary facilities, facades and the show gallery. Generated building renders and visuals for all client presentations.
- Worked as a Project Architect for 2 Addition and Alteration works. Administrated construction contracts, obtained clearances from regulatory agencies, reviewed shopdrawings, provided design directions and produced visuals for presentations.
- Worked on developing computational design workflows within Rhinoceros 3D + Grasshopper and Revit + Dynamo. I had made a simple pipeline to generate customised perforated panels within Rhinoceros 3D. I had come up with a prototype workflow that enables a massing model within Revit to be automatically generated based on inputs from an Excel sheet.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **National University of Singapore**

(2016-2017)Master of Arts, Architecture

Bachelor of Arts (Hons.

(2012-2016)Distinction), Architecture

#### SKILLS

### **CAD & Modelling**

Rhinoceros 3D	(proficient)
Grasshopper	(proficient)
AutoCAD	(proficient)
Sketchup	(proficient)
Revit	(prior exp)
Dynamo	(prior exp)

#### **Graphics & Rendering**

Photoshop	(proficient)
Illustrator	(proficient)
InDesign	(proficient)
Lumion	(proficient)
Vray	(prior exp)

#### **Programming Languages**

Python	(proficient)
C++	(basic proficiency)
Java	(prior exp)

## **Others**

ArcGIS	(basic proficiency)
Unreal	(prior exp)

#### LANGUAGES

English	(Native)
Mandarin	(Native)